Thomas Ingram

Apex, NC 27502 rg+hireme@ravinggenius.com m: 919 449.6305

Professional Summary

- · Self-taught programmer with strong desire to learn
- · Have worked with large datasets
- Have configured systems and networks professionally and personally
- · Linux evangelist and Open Source advocate
- Webmaster for many sites (some built from scratch and some CMS-based)
- Attend trade meetings and conferences regularly
- Technical advisor to several people

Technical Summary

Languages: HTML, CSS, Ruby, JavaScript | JSON, PHP, C#, VB, ColdFusion, ASP.NET, XML, Flex | AS3, VBA

Databases: SQLite, MySQL, MSSQL

Code Samples: http://github.com/ravinggenius

Tools: git, SVN, MVC, Rails, Sinatra, text editor, VIM, Visual Studio 2008

Other: REST, Regular Expressions, SharePoint

Future Interests: Agile, TDD, LISP, C++, NoSQL (especially MongoDB), Pair Programming, PostgreSQL, Graphic Design, Java (maybe), The Next Big Thing

Professional Experience

яandomByDesign; Freelancer | Owner; Apex, NC; 03/2007 - present

- Created a church CMS-backed website for a friend. Drupal, PHP, MySQL
- · Hand-crafted several websites for friends and family. Ruby, Sinatra, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

CISYS | Life Sciences; Web Developer; N Raleigh, NC; 11/2007 - 03/2010

- Built a SharePoint-backed IRB system from scratch with custom secure login C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Created several websites, primarily using ASP.NET technologies, including CISYS'. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, C#, VB.NET, PHP
- Advocated improved development methodologies, such as test-driven development
- Contracted with partner/vendor, Presentation Strategies. Supported existing reporting projects. Updated and maintained some websites. PHP, HTML, CSS, MSSQL, MySQL, XML, VBA

Sir Speedy Cary; Mail Room Supervisor | Web Developer; Cary, NC; 09/2005 - 10/2007

- Address and prepare letters and postcards for bulk mail.
- Cut paper, run deliveries, collate, hole punch and make computer recommendations.
- Built an online ordering system for our largest client to replace the old one. Extra features and polish were left undone due to time and budget constraints. PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL

Education

Sandhills Community College; Southern Pines, NC; 2001 spring

- · Accrued some basic credits
- Dropped out after a semester because of finances

Pensacola Christian College; Pensacola, FL; 2000 spring

- · Computer Science major
- · Dropped out after a semester because of excessive rules

Calvary Christian School; Southern Pines, NC; 1995 - 1999

• Chose electives that focused on Math, Physics and Logic

Certifications

• MySQL from Wake Tech